- For hundreds of years,
几百年来
analog computers were the most powerful computers on Earth,
模拟计算机是世界上最强大的计算机
predicting eclipses, tides, and guiding anti-aircraft guns.
被用来预测月食、潮汐和引导防空武器
Then, with the advent of solid-state transistors,
随着固态晶体管的出现
digital computers took off.
电子计算机蓬勃发展
Now, virtually every computer we use is digital.
现如今  几乎所有计算机都是电子的
But today, a perfect storm of factors is setting the scene
但是现在又有一波新趋势
for a resurgence of analog technology.
推动着模拟技术的复苏
This is an analog computer,
这是一台模拟计算机
and by connecting these wires in particular ways,
我可以通过特定的接线方式
I can program it to solve a whole range
给它编写程序
of differential equations.
让它解不同的微分方程
For example, this setup allows me to simulate
例如 我这样接线 就可以模拟一个带阻尼的重物在弹簧上振动
a damped mass oscillating on a spring.
So on the oscilloscope you can actually see
然后在示波器上 就能看到重物的位移随时间变化的图像
the position of the mass over time.
And I can vary the damping,
我还可以改变阻尼
or the spring constant,
或者弹簧的弹力系数
or the mass, and we can see
又或者重物的质量
how the amplitude and duration of the oscillations change.
就可以看到振幅和振动时长如何改变
Now what makes this an analog computer
而它之所以被称作模拟计算机
is that there are no zeros and ones in here.
是因为在它的概念里没有 0 和 1
Instead, there's actually a voltage that oscillates
而是真正的有一个电压
up and down exactly like a mass on a spring.
像重物在弹簧上一样上下振动
The electrical circuitry is an analog for the physical problem,
这个电子电路模拟了这个物理问题
it just takes place much faster.
使得运算快得多
Now, if I change the electrical connections,
现在如果我换一组接线
I can program this computer
就可以重新编程
to solve other differential equations,
算其他的微分方程
like the Lorenz system,
例如洛伦茨振子
which is a basic model of convection in the atmosphere.
这是大气对流的基本模型
Now the Lorenz system is famous because
它作为最早发现的混沌系统而闻名
it was one of the first discovered examples of chaos.
And here, you can see the Lorenz attractor
在屏幕上 你可以看到
with its beautiful butterfly shape.
洛伦茨吸引子美妙的蝴蝶图样
And on this analog computer,
在这台模拟计算机上
I can change the parameters
我可以实时地看到
and see their effects in real time.
我改变参数的效果
So these examples illustrate some
这几个例子展示了
of the advantages of analog computers.
模拟计算机的优势
They are incredibly powerful computing devices,
它十分强大
and they can complete a lot of computations fast.
运行得特别快
Plus, they don't take much power to do it.
而且 它还非常省电
With a digital computer,
在电子计算机里
if you wanna add two eight-bit numbers,
把两个八位二进制数相加
you need around 50 transistors,
需要大概 50 个晶体管
whereas with an analog computer,
而在模拟计算机里
you can add two currents,
只要连两根线
just by connecting two wires.
就能把两个电流相加
With a digital computer to multiply two numbers,
而用电子计算机计算两个数的乘积
you need on the order of 1,000 transistors
需要数以千计的晶体管
all switching zeros and ones,
在 0 和 1 之间反复横跳
whereas with an analog computer,
而在模拟计算机里
you can pass a current through a resistor,
只需要让电流流过一个电阻
and then the voltage across this resistor
这样流过这个电阻两端的电压
will be I times R.
就是 I*R 了
So effectively,
这就等效于
you have multiplied two numbers together.
你把两个数值做了乘法
But analog computers also have their drawbacks.
但是模拟计算机也有缺点
For one thing,
首先
they are not general-purpose computing devices.
它不是通用计算设备
I mean, you're not gonna run Microsoft Word on this thing.
在上面没法运行 Word
And also, since the inputs and outputs are continuous,
并且由于它的输入是连续的
I can't input exact values.
我并不能输入准确值
So if I try to repeat the same calculation,
因此重复相同的运算
I'm never going to get the exact same answer.
并不能得到相同的结果
Plus, think about manufacturing analog computers.
此外 在模拟计算机的制造过程中
There's always gonna be some variation
电阻、电容等元件的实际参数总是有所浮动
in the exact value of components,
like resistors or capacitors.
So as a general rule of thumb,
因此 一般来说
you can expect about a 1% error.
它大概会有 1% 的误差
So when you think of analog computers,
因此总结一下
you can think powerful, fast, and energy-efficient,
模拟计算机很强大 跑得很快 很省电
but also single-purpose, non-repeatable, and inexact.
但也有着用途单一、不可重复、不精确的缺点
And if those sound like deal-breakers,
如果这些东西听上去很差劲
it's because they probably are.
那么你是对的
I think these are the major reasons
我认为  以上这些理由
why analog computers fell out of favor
让电子计算机一出现
as soon as digital computers became viable.
就取代了模拟计算机
Now, here's why analog computers may be making a comeback.
现在我们来说说为什么模拟计算机可能重获青睐
It all starts with artificial intelligence.
这一切都源于人工智能的出现
- A machine has been programmed to see and to move objects.
这台机器经过编程  能看到物体、移动物体
- AI isn't new.
AI 并非新鲜事物
The term was coined back in 1956.
这个词早在 1956 年就被创造出来了
In 1958, Cornell University psychologist,
1958年  康奈尔大学的心理学家
Frank Rosenblatt, built the perceptron,
弗兰克·罗森布拉特  提出了感知机
designed to mimic how neurons fire in our brains.
来模仿人脑中的神经元发射信号的方式
So here's a basic model of how neurons in our brains work.
这是我们大脑中的神经元如何工作的基本模型
An individual neuron can either fire or not,
一个独立的神经元可以发射也可以不发射信号
so its level of activation can be represented
因此它的激活水平
as a one or a zero.
就可以表示为 0 或者 1
The input to one neuron
一个神经元的输入
is the output from a bunch of other neurons,
是其他一堆神经元的输出
but the strength of these connections between neurons varies,
但因为这些神经元之间的连接强度不同
so each one can be given a different weight.
所以每一个连接都有不同的权重
Some connections are excitatory,
有些连接起到刺激作用
so they have positive weights,
因此它们的权重是正的
while others are inhibitory,
另外一些连接起到抑制作用
so they have negative weights.
因此它们的权重是负的
And the way to figure out whether a particular neuron fires,
要判断某个神经元是否发射信号
is to take the activation of each input neuron
可以将它的每个输入神经元的激活水平
and multiply by its weight,
乘以它们的权重
and then add these all together.
再累加起来
If their sum is greater than some number called the bias,
如果它们的和大于某个数字（偏差）
then the neuron fires,
那么这个神经元就发射信号
but if it's less than that, the neuron doesn't fire.
如果小于偏差 那么就不发射
As input, Rosenblatt's perceptron had 400 photocells
罗森布拉特的感知机以 400 个感光器作为输入
arranged in a square grid,
感光器会排成正方形网格
to capture a 20 by 20-pixel image.
来捕捉 20×20 像素的图像
You can think of each pixel as an input neuron,
你可以认为每一个像素都是一个输入神经元
with its activation being the brightness of the pixel.
它的激活水平就是这个像素的亮度
Although strictly speaking,
严格来说
the activation should be either zero or one,
激活水平必须是 0 或 1
we can let it take any value between zero and one.
但我们可以让它取 0 到 1 之间的任何一个值
All of these neurons are connected to a single output neuron,
所有这些神经元都会连向一个输出神经元
each via its own adjustable weight.
每条连接都有一个可调节的权重
So to see if the output neuron will fire,
所以  要知道输出神经元是否发射信号
you multiply the activation of each neuron by its weight,
你可以将每个神经元的激活水平乘以它们的权重
and add them together.
再相加
This is essentially a vector dot product.
这个过程本质上是求向量点积
If the answer is larger than the bias, the neuron fires,
如果结果大于偏差  那么输出神经元发射信号
and if not, it doesn't.
反之不发射
Now the goal of the perceptron
现在  感知机的目标
was to reliably distinguish between two images,
是准确地分辨两张图片
like a rectangle and a circle.
比如分辨长方形和圆形
For example,
举个例子
the output neuron could always fire when presented with a circle,
当出现圆形时  输出神经元就会发射信号
but never when presented with a rectangle.
如果是长方形  那么它永远也不会发射信号
To achieve this, the perception had to be trained,
为了达到这个目的  我们需要训练感知机
that is, shown a series of different circles
也就是给它看一系列不同的圆形和长方形
and rectangles, and have its weights adjusted accordingly.
从而改变它的神经元连接权重
We can visualize the weights as an image,
因为图片的每个像素都有一个唯一的权重
since there's a unique weight for each pixel of the image.
所以我们可以把所有权重可视化为一张图像
Initially, Rosenblatt set all the weights to zero.
开始时  罗森布拉特把所有权重设置为 0
If the perceptron's output is correct,
如果感知机的输出正确
for example, here it's shown a rectangle
比如说  现在出现的是一个长方形
and the output neuron doesn't fire,
而且输出神经元没有发射信号
no change is made to the weights.
那么权重不会发生变化
But if it's wrong, then the weights are adjusted.
但如果感知机的输出是错的  就会调整权重
The algorithm for updating the weights
更新权重的算法非常简单
is remarkably simple.
Here, the output neuron didn't fire
现在给感知机展示的是一个圆形
when it was supposed to because it was shown a circle.
输出神经元应该发射信号  但它没有
So to modify the weights,
所以要修改权重
you simply add the input activations to the weights.
你可以简单地把输入激活水平加到权重上
If the output neuron fires when it shouldn't,
如果输出神经元在它不该发射信号时  发射了信号
like here, when shown a rectangle,
比如现在给它展示了一个长方形（但它发射了信号）
well, then you subtract the input activations from the weights,
你就要从权重上减去输入激活水平
and you keep doing this
一直重复进行这些操作
until the perceptron correctly identifies all the training images.
直到感知机能正确辨识  训练集里所有的图片
It was shown that this algorithm will always converge,
事实表明  这个算法一定会收敛
so long as it's possible to map the two categories
前提是能把这两类图片映射到不同的组中
into distinct groups.
The perceptron was capable
感知机能够区分不同的形状
of distinguishing between different shapes
比如长方形和三角形
like rectangles and triangles, or between different letters.
它也可以区分不同的字母
And according to Rosenblatt,
据罗森布拉特所说
it could even tell the difference between cats and dogs.
它甚至还能区分猫和狗
He said the machine was capable
他说感知机能够提出
of what amounts to original thought,
相当于是原创的想法
and the media lapped it up.
媒体也大力赞扬感知机
The "New York Times" called the perceptron
纽约时报是这样评价感知机的：
"the embryo of an electronic computer
它是电子计算机的雏形
that the Navy expects will be able to walk, talk,
海军希望它未来能走路、能说话、
see, write, reproduce itself,
能看东西、能写字、能自我复制
and be conscious of its existence."
甚至能意识到自己的存在
- After training on lots of examples,
- 在经过大量训练后
it's given new faces it has never seen,
感知机会收到它从未见过的人脸图片
and is able to successfully distinguish male from female.
并且能够正确分辨这个人是男是女
It has learned.
它已经学会了
- In reality, the perceptron was pretty limited in what it could do.
实际上 感知机能做的事相当有限
It could not, in fact, tell apart dogs from cats.
其实它并不能区分猫和狗
This and other critiques were raised
1969年 麻省理工学院的巨头明斯基和帕珀特
in a book by MIT giants, Minsky and Papert, in 1969.
在书中指出了这一点  并给出了其他批评意见
And that led to a bust period
人工神经网络和整个人工智能
for artificial neural networks and AI in general.
因此陷入了萧条期
It's known as the first AI winter.
这被称为人工智能的第一个冬天
Rosenblatt did not survive this winter.
罗森布拉特没能熬过这个冬天
He drowned while sailing in Chesapeake Bay
他在 43 岁生日当天  在切萨皮克湾驾船时溺水身亡
on his 43rd birthday.
- The NAV Lab is a road-worthy truck,
- NAV 实验室是一辆适航性货车
modified so that researchers or computers
它被改造后 能根据情况与需求
can control the vehicle as occasion demands.
由被研究员或电脑来操控
- In the 1980s, there was an AI resurgence
- 在20世纪80年代 卡耐基·梅隆大学的研究员在创造出其中一台
when researchers at Carnegie Mellon
当时世界上最早的自动驾驶汽车的时候
created one of the first self-driving cars.
曾经使人工智能一度再次兴起
The vehicle was steered by an artificial neural network
这辆车子的转向 是由一个叫 ALVINN 的人工神经网络来控制的
called ALVINN.
It was similar to the perceptron,
它有点像感知器
except it had a hidden layer of artificial neurons
只不过它在输入与输出之间
between the input and output.
有一层隐藏起来的人工神经元
As input, ALVINN received
作为输入端  ALVINN 以 30*32 像素的图像
30 by 32-pixel images of the road ahead.
接收前面的路的信息
Here, I'm showing them as 60 by 64 pixels.
在这里我将以60*64像素的清晰度来呈现
But each of these input neurons was connected
但每一个输入的神经元都透过一个可调整的权重
via an adjustable weight to a hidden layer of four neurons.
被连接到一层隐藏起来的4个神经元
These were each connected to 32 output neurons.
而所有的这些隐藏层神经元 都连接到32个输出神经元
So to go from one layer of the network to the next,
因此要从这网络的一层去到它的下一层
you perform a matrix multiplication:
你必须要进行一次矩阵乘法
the input activation times the weights.
输入激励乘以权重
The output neuron with the greatest activation
输出神经元和最大的激励
determines the steering angle.
决定了方向盘的转动角度
To train the neural net,
要训练这个神经网络
a human drove the vehicle,
需要一个人去开这辆车
providing the correct steering angle for a given input image.
提供对于一个给定图像的正确的转动角
All the weights in the neural network
所有在这个神经网络里面的权重
were adjusted through the training
都在训练过程中被调整了
so that ALVINN's output better matched that of the human driver.
这样能使 ALVINN 的输出能与人类司机更匹配
The method for adjusting the weights
调整权重的方法
is called backpropagation,
被称为反向传播算法
which I won't go into here,
这我不会在这里深入探讨
but Welch Labs has a great series on this,
但 Welch Labs  频道有一系列的影片讲解这个算法
which I'll link to in the description.
Again, you can visualize the weights
话说回来 你可以将这四个隐藏层神经元的权重
for the four hidden neurons as images.
视觉化成图像
The weights are initially set to be random,
在一开始 权重将被设置为随机数
but as training progresses,
但随着训练进行着
the computer learns to pick up on certain patterns.
计算机学会了如何去选一个特定的模式
You can see the road markings emerge in the weights.
你可以看到路的标线出现在那些权重里
Simultaneously, the output steering angle coalesces
而在同时 输出的转向角
onto the human steering angle.
也在朝人类转向的模式靠近
The computer drove the vehicle at a top speed
计算机以每小时1-2公里的最高速度驾驶着这台汽车
of around one or two kilometers per hour.
It was limited by the speed
限制它最高速度的瓶颈
at which the computer could perform matrix multiplication.
是这台计算机进行矩阵乘法的速度极限
Despite these advances,
尽管取得了这些进展
artificial neural networks still struggled with seemingly simple tasks,
人工神经网络仍然很难完成看似简单的任务
like telling apart cats and dogs.
像分辨猫和狗之类的
And no one knew whether hardware or software was the weak link.
而且没有人知道这短板到底是来源于硬件还是软件
I mean, did we have a good model of intelligence,
换句话说 我们是否拥有一个很智能的模型
we just needed more computer power?
而我们所需要的 仅仅是更强的计算性能？
Or, did we have the wrong idea
抑或是 我们对如何构建智能系统
about how to make intelligence systems altogether?
拥有着完全错误的观念
So artificial intelligence
experienced another lull in the 1990s.
所以人工智能 在20世纪90年代陷入了另一个低谷
By the mid 2000s,
直到 2000 年代中期
most AI researchers were focused on improving algorithms.
大多数人工智能研究者都专注于改进算法
But one researcher, Fei-Fei Li,
但有一位研究者——李飞飞
thought maybe there was a different problem.
认为或许该另觅他路
Maybe these artificial neural networks
可能这些人工神经网络
just needed more data to train on.
只是需要更多数据去训练
So she planned to map out the entire world of objects.
因此 她计划制作整个物体世界的地图
From 2006 to 2009, she created ImageNet,
2006 年到 2009 年期间 她创立了 ImageNet
a database of 1.2 million human-labeled images,
一个包含 120 万张人工标注图像的数据库
which at the time,
在当时 是有史以来最大的标记图像数据集
was the largest labeled image dataset ever constructed.
And from 2010 to 2017,
从 2010 年到 2017 年
ImageNet ran an annual contest:
ImageNet 举办每年一度的竞赛
the ImageNet Large Scale Visual Recognition Challenge,
ImageNet 大规模视觉识别挑战赛（ILSVRC）
where software programs competed
让软件程序互相竞争
to correctly detect and classify images.
试图正确检测和分类图像
Images were classified into 1,000 different categories,
测试用图像分为 1000 个不同类别
including 90 different dog breeds.
其中包括 90 个不同犬种
A neural network competing in this competition
参与这场比拼的神经网络
would have an output layer of 1,000 neurons,
输出层包含 1000 个神经元
each corresponding to a category of object
分别对应图像中出现的 1000 个物体大类
that could appear in the image.
If the image contains, say, a German shepherd,
如果图像中包含 比方说 一只德国牧羊犬
then the output neuron corresponding to German shepherd
那么对应德国牧羊犬的那个输出神经元
should have the highest activation.
就应该激活最高的输出
Unsurprisingly, it turned out to be a tough challenge.
不出所料 事实证明这是一项艰巨的挑战
One way to judge the performance of an AI
评判 AI 性能的一种方式
is to see how often the five highest neuron activations
是看激活输出最高的 5 个神经元
do not include the correct category.
均不是正确类别的频率
This is the so-called top-5 error rate.
这就是所谓的 Top-5 错误率
In 2010, the best performer had a top-5 error rate of 28.2%,
2010 年 表现最佳的程序达到了 28.2%
meaning that nearly 1/3 of the time,
这意味着在近三分之一的测试中
the correct answer was not among its top five guesses.
正确答案都不在其前 5 个猜测之列
In 2011, the error rate of the best performer was 25.8%,
2011 年 这个数字降低到 25.8%
a substantial improvement.
这是很大的进步
But the next year,
但是接下来的一年
an artificial neural network
来自多伦多大学的人工神经网络 AlexNet
from the University of Toronto, called AlexNet,
blew away the competition
以低至 16.4% 的 Top-5 错误率碾压对手
with a top-5 error rate of just 16.4%.
What set AlexNet apart was its size and depth.
AlexNet 的规模和深度使之与众不同
The network consisted of eight layers,
该网络共有个 8 神经层
and in total, 500,000 neurons.
总共包含 50 万神经元
To train AlexNet,
要训练 AlexNet 得通过训练集
60 million weights and biases had to be carefully adjusted
小心调整 6000 万个权重与偏置
using the training database.
Because of all the big matrix multiplications,
由于这些巨大的矩阵乘法运算
processing a single image required 700 million
处理一张图片需要 7 亿次简单数学运算
individual math operations.
So training was computationally intensive.
因此 训练它 是计算密集的
The team managed it by pioneering the use of GPUs,
它的团队开创性地使用 GPU 完成计算
graphical processing units,
GPU 即图形处理单元
which are traditionally used for driving displays, screens.
通常用于驱动显示器、屏幕等
So they're specialized for fast parallel computations.
因此适合快速并行计算
The AlexNet paper describing their research
描述他们研究的 AlexNet 论文引起轰动
is a blockbuster.
It's now been cited over 100,000 times,
现在已经被引用十万余次
and it identifies the scale of the neural network
论文认为 神经网络的规模是其成功的关键
as key to its success.
It takes a lot of computation to train and run the network,
训练和运行这一网络需要大量的计算
but the improvement in performance is worth it.
但相较于性能的提升 是值得的
With others following their lead,
在后来者的努力下
the top-5 error rate on the ImageNet competition
ImageNet 挑战赛的 Top-5 错误率
plummeted in the years that followed,
在随后的几年直线下降
down to 3.6% in 2015.
到 2015 年已经降至 3.6%
That is better than human performance.
这已经超越了人类表现
The neural network that achieved this
实现这一目标的神经网络包含 100 个神经层
had 100 layers of neurons.
So the future is clear:
所以未来是明确的
We will see ever increasing demand
我们将看到对更大神经网络的需求不断增长
for ever larger neural networks.
And this is a problem for several reasons:
从数个方面来看 这都是一个问题
One is energy consumption.
其一是能源消耗
Training a neural network requires an amount
训练一个神经网络所需的电量
of electricity similar to the yearly consumption
相当于三个家庭的一年的用电量
of three households.
Another issue is the so-called
另一个问题被称为
冯·诺伊曼瓶颈
Virtually every modern digital computer
几乎所有现代数字计算机都将数据存入内存
stores data in memory,
and then accesses it as needed over a bus.
然后按照需要 通过一条总线访问它
When performing the huge matrix multiplications
当执行深度神经网络所需的大量矩阵乘法时
required by deep neural networks,
most of the time and energy
大部分时间和能源都用于获取这些数值
goes into fetching those weight values
rather than actually doing the computation.
而不是实际的数学运算
And finally, there are the limitations of Moore's Law.
最后 还有摩尔定律的局限性
For decades, the number of transistors on a chip
几十年来 芯片上的晶体管数量约两年翻一番
has been doubling approximately every two years,
but now the size of a transistor
但现在晶体管的尺寸已经接近原子大小
is approaching the size of an atom.
So there are some fundamental physical challenges
因此进一步小型化
to further miniaturization.
在物理原理上面临挑战
So this is the perfect storm for analog computers.
因此 模拟计算机正逢其时
Digital computers are reaching their limits.
数字计算机正在接近其极限
Meanwhile, neural networks are exploding in popularity,
与此同时 神经网络正在爆炸式发展
and a lot of what they do boils down to a single task:
其所需的大部分操作 归结为一个单一任务
matrix multiplication.
矩阵乘法
Best of all, neural networks
最重要的是 神经网络不需要数字计算机提供的精度
don't need the precision of digital computers.
Whether the neural net is 96% or 98% confident
神经网络若认为图中包含一只鸡
the image contains a chicken,
不论置信度是 96% 或 98%
it doesn't really matter, it's still a chicken.
归根结底那仍是一只鸡
So slight variability in components
因此 零件和环境的轻微变化是可以容忍的
or conditions can be tolerated.
I went to an analog computing startup in Texas,
我造访了德州的一家初创公司
called Mythic AI.
Mythic AI （迷思智能？）
Here, they're creating analog chips to run neural networks.
他们在这里创制模拟芯片以运行神经网络
And they demonstrated several AI algorithms for me.
并且为我展示了几项人工智能算法
- Oh, there you go.
哦 快看
See, it's getting you.
它认出你了
Yeah. - That's fascinating.
是的 - 这超棒的
- The biggest use case is augmented and virtual reality.
它主要应用在增强现实和虚拟现实中
If your friend is in a different,
如果你的朋友们天各一方
they're at their house and you're at your house,
他们和你分别在各自家中
you can actually render each other in the virtual world.
你们要能在虚拟世界中渲染出对方的样子
So it needs to really quickly capture your pose,
这就需要高效的动作捕捉
and then render it in the VR world.
以及在 VR 世界中的渲染
- So, hang on, is this for the metaverse thing?
所以 等等 这是给元宇宙准备的吗
- Yeah, this is a very metaverse application.
是的 这是个很有元宇宙范的应用
This is depth estimation from just a single webcam.
这是基于单摄像头的景深估计
It's just taking this scene,
它只是拍摄了这幅画面
and then it's doing a heat map.
然后把它转换成热力图
So if it's bright, it means it's close.
图上亮的地方意味着更靠近一些
And if it's far away, it makes it like black.
如果离远一些 颜色就会变深
- Now all these algorithms can be run on digital computers,
- 目前以上所有算法都能在数字计算机上运行
but here, the matrix multiplication
但是在这里 矩阵乘法
is actually taking place in the analog domain.
其实是在模拟域进行的
To make this possible,
为了实现这一点
Mythic has repurposed digital flash storage cells.
Mythic 调整了数字闪存单元的用途
Normally these are used as memory
它们一般被用作内存
to store either a one or a zero.
每一位上记录的要么是1 要么是0
If you apply a large positive voltage to the control gate,
如果你在控制门上施加较大的电压
electrons tunnel up through an insulating barrier
电子将隧穿通过绝缘层
and become trapped on the floating gate.
并被限制在悬浮门中
Remove the voltage,
即使撤去电压
and the electrons can remain on the floating gate for decades,
这些电子能在悬浮门中停留数十年
preventing the cell from conducting current.
阻止闪存单元导通
And that's how you can store either a one or a zero.
这样就能在单元中存储1或者0
You can read out the stored value by applying a small voltage.
施加较小的电压就能读出存储的值
If there are electrons on the floating gate,
如果有电子在悬浮门中
no current flows, so that's a zero.
单元中没有电流流过 代表0
If there aren't electrons,
如果悬浮门中没有电子
then current does flow, and that's a one.
则电流可以流过 这代表1
Now Mythic's idea is
现在 Mythic 的想法是
to use these cells not as on/off switches,
把这些单元用作可变电阻
but as variable resistors.
而不是开关
They do this
他们在每个悬浮门中
by putting a specific number of electrons on each floating gate,
放置指定数量的电子
instead of all or nothing.
而不是非空即满
The greater the number of electrons,
悬浮门中电子越多
the higher the resistance of the channel.
通道中的电阻就越高
When you later apply a small voltage,
如果之后在其上施加较小的电压
the current that flows is equal to V over R.
电流就等于 V 除以 R
But you can also think of this as voltage times conductance,
但你也可以把它视作电压与电导的乘积
where conductance is just the reciprocal of resistance.
其中电导是电阻的倒数
So a single flash cell can be used
于是一个单独的闪存单元
to multiply two values together, voltage times conductance.
可以对两个值做乘法 即电压乘以电导
So to use this to run an artificial neural network,
所以要用这种方法运行一个人工神经网络
well they first write all the weights to the flash cells
他们会首先将所有的权重作为电导
as each cell's conductance.
写入闪存
Then, they input the activation values
然后 他们将激活值
as the voltage on the cells.
作为电压施加在单元两端
And the resulting current is the product
所得的结果就是
of voltage times conductance,
电压和电导的乘积
which is activation times weight.
也即激活函数的激活值乘以权重
The cells are wired together in such a way
这些单元相互连接
that the current from each multiplication adds together,
可以对每处乘法的结果求和
completing the matrix multiplication.
这样就实现了矩阵乘法
- So this is our first product.
- 这是我们的第一件产品
This can do 25 trillion math operations per second.
它每秒能完成 25 万亿次数学运算
- 25 trillion.
- 25 万亿次
- Yep, 25 trillion math operations per second,
- 没错 每秒25万亿次数学运算
in this little chip here,
这块小小芯片
burning about three watts of power.
功耗大约是 3 瓦特
- How does it compare to a digital chip?
- 它与数字芯片相比起来如何
- The newer digital systems can do anywhere
较新的数字元件能在一秒内
from 25 to 100 trillion operations per second,
完成 25 万亿到 100 万亿次数学运算
but they are big, thousand-dollar systems
但是那都是些庞大而昂贵的系统 价值数千美元
that are spitting out 50 to 100 watts of power.
它们的功率在 50 到 100 瓦特
- Obviously this isn't
- 显然
like an apples apples comparison, right?
这两者是没法相比的 对吧
- No, it's not apples to apples.
- 不 完全没法比
I mean, training those algorithms,
我的意思是
you need big hardware like this.
你需要这些大家伙来训练神经网络
You can just do all sorts of stuff on the GPU,
你可以在 GPU 上完成所有这些事
but if you specifically are doing AI workloads
但是如果你想应用某个 AI
and you wanna deploy 'em, you could use this instead.
并且部署它们 就可以使用芯片来替代 GPU
You can imagine them in security cameras,
不难想象它们在安保摄像头
autonomous systems,
自动化系统
inspection equipment for manufacturing.
流水线检测中的应用
Every time they make a Frito-Lay chip,
每生产一包乐事薯片
they inspect it with a camera,
他们会用一个摄像头检查它
and the bad Fritos get blown off of the conveyor belt.
然后移除传送带上的次品
But they're using artificial intelligence
他们是在用人工智能
to spot which Fritos are good and bad.
检查产品的质量
- Some have proposed
有人提议在智能家居音箱中采用模拟芯片
using analog circuitry in smart home speakers,
solely to listen for the wake word, like Alexa or Siri.
来单独监听唤醒词 像是 Alexa 或者 Siri
They would use a lot less power
这样可以降低功耗
and be able to quickly and reliably turn on
同时能够稳定而快速地启动
the digital circuitry of the device.
设备的数字电路
But you still have to deal with the challenges of analog.
但是模拟信号中的挑战仍然亟待解决
- So for one of the popular networks,
- 对于一个最为流行的神经网络
there would be 50 sequences of matrix multiplies that you're doing.
其中有 50 个序列的矩阵乘法需要完成
Now, if you did that entirely in the analog domain,
现在如果你完全在模拟域进行计算
by the time it gets to the output,
在输出时
it's just so distorted that you don't have any result at all.
信号会极度失真以至于完全得不到结果
So you convert it from the analog domain,
所以需要把信号从模拟域
back to the digital domain,
转换回数字域
send it to the next processing block,
将它送入下一个处理模块
and then you convert it into the analog domain again.
然后再把它转换到模拟域
And that allows you to preserve the signal.
这样就可以避免信号失真
- You know, when Rosenblatt was first setting
所以  当罗森布拉特首次搭建感知机的时候
up his perceptron,
he used a digital IBM computer.
用的还是IBM的数字计算机
Finding it too slow,
但发现它太慢了
he built a custom analog computer,
随后又搭建了定制的模拟计算机
complete with variable resistors
这回用的是变阻器和小电机来驱动
and little motors to drive them.
Ultimately, his idea of neural networks
最终  人们发现他神经网络的想法是正确的
turned out to be right.
Maybe he was right about analog, too.
也许他的模拟计算机也会是正确的
Now, I can't say whether analog computers
现在  我也不确定模拟计算机能否走上
will take off the way digital did last century,
数字计算机在上个世纪的光辉道路
but they do seem to be better suited
但是有些时候  模拟计算机更适合
to a lot of the tasks that we want computers to perform today,
处理人们现在需要的计算任务
which is a little bit funny
有趣的是
because I always thought of digital
我总以为数字技术是处理信息的最佳选项
as the optimal way of processing information.
Everything from music to pictures,
从音乐到照片再到视频
to video has all gone digital in the last 50 years.
我们身边的一切  在过去的50年里都变成了数字媒体
But maybe in a 100 years,
但也许再过一百年
we will look back on digital,
我们回望数字技术的时候
not as the end point of information technology,
发现它不是信息技术的终点
but as a starting point.
而是起点
Our brains are digital in that a neuron either fires or it doesn't,
神经元信号的发射（1）与不发射（0）代表的大脑是数字式的
but they're also analog
但是他们也是模拟的
in that thinking takes place everywhere, all at once.
我们思考的过程是同时发生在大脑各处的
So maybe what we need to achieve true artificial intelligence,
因此  我们要想实现真正的人工智能
machines that think like us,
造出像人类一样思考的机器
is the power of analog.
模拟的力量也许真的不可或缺